Chapter 10.
He found himself in the neighborhood of the asteroids
325,-326,-327,-328,-329, and 330..
He began, therefore, by visiting them, in order to add to his knowledge.
The first of them was inhabited by a king.
Clad in royal purple and irman he was seated upon a throne which was at the
same time both simple and majestic.
"Ah!
Here is a subject," exclaimed the king, when he saw the little prince coming.
And the little prince asked himself: "How could he recognize me when he had
never seen me before?"
He did not know how the world is simplified for kings. To them, all men are subjects.
"Approach, so that I may see you better," said to the king, who felt consumingly
proud of being at last a king over somebody.
The little prince looked everywhere to find a place to sit down; but the entire
planet was crammed and obstructed by the king's magnificent Urban robe.
So he remained standing upright, and, since he was tired, he yawned
which is contrary to etiquette to yawn in the presence of a king mnemonic said to him.
"I forbid you to do so hi I can't help it.
I can't stop myself why the little prince, thoroughly embarrassed.
"I have come on a long journey, and I've had no sleep..."
"Ah, then," the king said.
"I order you to yawn.
It is yeah since I have seen anyone yawning you're honest to me ah objects of curiosity.
Come, now you and again!
It is an order."
"That frightens me... I I I I cannot anymore the little prince, now completely abashed hmm
reply the king.
"Then I um I order you sometimes to yawn and sometimes to--"
He splittered a little, and seemed vexed.
For what the king fundamentally insisted upon was that his authority should be
respected. He tolerated no disobedience.
He was an absolute monarch. But, because he was a very good man, he made his orders reasonable.
"If I ordered a general," he would say, by way of example, "if I ordered a general to
change himself into a c word and if the general did not obey me, that would not
be the fault of the general.
It would be my fault."
"May I sit down okay now a timid inquiry from the little prince.
"I order you to do so," the king answered him, and majestically gathered in a fold
of his Urban mantle.
But the little prince was wondering...
The planet was so tiny.
Over what could this king really rule Messiah he said to him,
"I begged that you will excuse me asking you a question--"
"I ordered you to ask me a question," the king hastened to assure him Saya
over what do you rule?"
"Over everything," said the king, with magnificent simplicity.
"Over everything?"
The king made a gesture, which took in his planet, the other planets, and all the stars.
"Over all that ask the little prince.
"Over all that," the king answered.
For his rule was not only absolute: it was also universal.
"And the stars obey you?"
"Certainly they do," the king said.
"They obey instantly.
I do not permit insubordination."
Such power was a thing for the little prince to marvel at.
If he had been a master of such complete authority, he would have been able to
watch the sunset, not 44 times in one day, but 72 or even a hundred, or even 200
times, without ever having to move his chair.
And because he felt a bit sad as he remembered his little planet, which he had forsaken,
he plucked up his courage to ask the king a favor
I should like to see a sunset...
do me that kindness...
Order the sun to set..."
"If I ordered a general to fly from one flower to another like a butterfly, or to
write a tragic drama, or to change himself into a seabird and if the
general did not carry out the order that he had received,
which one of us would be in the wrong?"
the king demanded.
"The general, or myself?"
"You sent the prince firmly.
"Exactly. One must require from each one the duty which each one can perform," the king went on.
"Accepted authority rests first of all on reason.
If you ordered your people to go and throw themselves into the CE they would
rise up in revolution.
I have the right to require obedience because my orders are reasonable."
"Then my sunset?" the little prince reminded him but he never forgot a
question once he had asked it.
"You shall have your sunset. I shall command it.
But, according to my science of government, I shall wait until conditions are favorable
When will that be?" inquired the little prince
reply to the king; and before saying anything else he consulted a bulky almanac hmm
That will be about--
[Music]
that will be this evening about 20 minutes to wait
hmm you will see how well I have obeyed."
The little prince yawned.
He was regretting his lost sunset.
And then two he was already beginning to be a little bored.
"I have nothing more to do here," he said to the king.
"So I shall set out on my way again."
"Do not go," said the king, who was very proud of having a subject.
"Do not go.
I will make you a Minister!"
"Minister of what minister of-- of Justice there is nobody here to judge!"
"We do not know that," the king said to him.
"I have not yet made a complete tour of my kingdom I'm very old.
There is no room here for the carriage.
And it tires me to walk."
"Oh, but I've looked already set the little prince, turning around to
give one more glance to the other side of the planet.
On that side, as on this, there was nobody at all... "Then you shall
judge yourself," the king answered. "that is the most difficult thing of all. It is
much more difficult to judge oneself than to judge others. If you succeed in
judging yourself rightly when you are indeed a man of true wisdom."
"Yes set the little prince I can judge myself anywhere.
I do not need to live on this planet hmm say it to the king.
"I have good reason to believe that somewhere on my planet there is an old rat.
I hear him at night.
You can judge this old rat.
From time to time we will condemn him to death.
Thus his life will depend on your justice.
But you will pardon him on each occasion; for he must be treated thriftly
He is the only one we have."
"I," replied the little prince, "do not like to condemn anyone to death.
And now I think I will go on my way."
"No," said the king.
But the little prince, having now completed his preparations for departure,
had no wish to grieve the old monarch Majesty wishes to be promptly obeyed," he
said, "he should be able to give me a reasonable order.
He should be able, for example, to order me to be gone by the end of one minute.
It seems to me that conditions are favorable As the king made no answer, the little
prince hesitated a moment.
Then, with a sigh, he took his leave.
"I make you my Ambassador called out easterly He had a magnificent heir of authority
oops are very strange," the little prince said to himself, as he continued on his journey